#大家好 這個西紅柿哦
Hi everyone! The tomatoes,
#這裡長了那(麼)[SIC]大(的)[SIC]一棵西紅沛出來
A big tomato plant is growing up here.
#可能是上次小豬吃得[SIC]那個西紅沛
Perhaps the piggy pooed here last time,
#拉(痾)了一堆屎在這里
after eating tomatoes.
#又長出一個苗出來
So a seedling started growing.
#現在長那邊[SIC]多個西紅杮出來
Now here are so many tomatoes.
#還有兩個紅的哦
And two of them are red.
#這西紅杮很好吃的
This tomato is very tasty.
#野生的
It's wild.
#就跟野生的差不多
There's no difference from the wild ones.
#我們都沒施過肥
We didn't even put any fertilizer.
#很好吃
Tasty!
#你看 這個果肉
Look! The tomato,
#很結實 (沒有)買得是很軟的 這個很結實的
is very firm. The tomatoes bought from the markets are soft. But this is very firm.
#啊~
Ah!
#這個 果汁
The, juice...
#這還有一個
There's one more.
#紅的是可以吃的
The red ones can be eaten.
#嗯
Um?
#這怎麼爛啦
Why is it rotten?
#沒爛 就這樣子的
No. It's just how it looks.
#這抺一下 更好看
Wipe it. So that it looks better.
#哇 你看
Wa! Look!
#你個沒施過肥的
It has never been fertilized.
#很有西紅杮的味道的
So it's very flavourful,
#味道也很濃
and rich too.
#全都是青的
All are green.
#幸好那個小豬沒發現
Fortunately that piggy did not discover the tomatoes.
#被它發現啦 啥都完啦
Otherwise, game over.
#苗都被它啃掉啦
Not even a seedling can be spared.
#那條豬 那條小豬比較笨
That pig, that piggy is rather stupid.
#看還有沒有
Let me see if there're any more.
#你看
Look!
#一串一串的 好靚哦
Strings of tomatoes. It's really beautiful!
#下次我沒菜吃的時候就可以摘來吃
I can pick some when I run of food next time.
今年的橘子一個都不長 (註︰其實我不太知道甚麼是橘子，是橙和柑桔之類的嗎？)
There's not even a single citrus this year.
#去年長了好多橘子的這上面
There were a lot of citrus up there last year.
#今年一個都沒有
But there's not even one this year.
#不知道是不是
Is it because,
#沒有施肥 還是怎麼樣
I didn't put any fertilizer? Or whatever?
#我們摘點來喂豬
Let's pick some for the pig.
#青的 可以
The green ones, are good.
#剛好這裡
Right here,
#剛好 剛好這裡有一個爆的
right, right here I see a cracked one.
#這個爆的給它吃
This cracked tomato is for it.
#哎呀 有點紅哦
Ayo! It's a bit red.
#摘幾個不好看的 不挸的 給小豬吃
Get some not attractive, not beautiful ones, for the pig.
#靚的留給我吃
The beautiful ones are left for me.
#你看 這個有疤的
Look! There's a scar on it.
#摘給小豬吃 (註︰原字幕出錯)
Pick it for the pig.
#你看 這個有疤的
Look! Here's a scar.
#還有其他太小啦
The rest are too small.
#沒有不好看的啦
No more unattractive ones.
#啊 這有一個很醜的
Ah! This one is very ugly.
#你看 這裡都一個長了一個洞的
Look! There's a hole on this tomato.
#等一下給小豬吃
It's for the piggy.
#我不給它吃那麼多 小豬
I'm not giving it too much, the piggy.
#就給它那麼一點點就夠啦
Just a bit here is already enough.
#我們把它送上去給它吃一下
Let's bring them up there for it.
#這兩條狗 去去去~走走走走走~
These two dogs... Go, go! Let's go!
#你看那條豬 默默的看著我
Look! The pig is staring at me silently.
#肯定看上我手上的東西啦
It must attracted by what I am carrying
#上次我抓 抓它 (註︰原字幕沒有口吃)
Last time I caught, caught it.
#它好怕我了 現在
It's now very scared of me.
#扔給它吃 小豬
Throw it the tomatoes. Piggy!
#給好吃的給你吃
I have some good food for you.
#不敢來
It's still scared.
#你看這個狗
Look that the dogs!
#多管閒事
Nosy!
#又不是給你吃的
The tomatoes are not for you.
#你會吃素嗎
You eat veggies?
#竟然拿來當球來踢
It's just a ball for them.
#叼給我
Take it!
#快點 叼給我
Come on! Take it!
#不聽話
Naughty!
#你看 這條豬像沒睡醒的樣
Look! The pig looks very sleepy.
#來 給點好吃的給你吃
Come! I have something tasty for you.
#我一靠近它 它就跑
It simply runs away whenever I get close to it.
#吃啊 今天我又不抓你
Just eat! I'm not going to catch you today.
#真是的 吃多啦 (註︰其實不太明白這句)
Come on! Eat more!
#不給你吃 (註︰由這句的語氣估計他上一句說甚麼的)
I've changed my mind.
#給給
Ha ha
#給給 等一下啊
Ha ha! Hold on!
#你看 開始 開始
Look! Let's go, let's go!
#今天我又抓你來秤一下啦
I will catch you onto the scale today.
#差不多四五(十)[SIC]斤呀 這條豬
This pig is almost fifty "jin". (1 jin = 500 grams)
#那麼肥 抱都抱不動
It's so fat! I can only barely hold it.
#這樣不行 要站上去
No no no! You have to stand onto it.
#哈哈 倆個人一起上來
Ha ha. Together, both of us.
#是不是 這樣不好秤
See? It's really hard.
#秤得到
No, it's fine.
#200
Two hundred
#2601 你看
Two hundred and sixty. Right?
#哎呦
Ayo!
#262
Two hundred and sixty two
#把這個小豬屎都嚇出來啦
We scared the poo out of it.
#沖乾淨
Let me clean the place.
#我們秤一下我們多重 就知道小豬有多重啦
We'll weight ourselves. Then we can get the weight of the piggy.
#205
Two hundred, and five
Two hundred and five
#205減去
Two hundred and five minus
#算一下
You calculate.
#57 [斤] (註︰字幕有「斤」字，但其實沒有說)
Fifty seven (28.5 kg)
#57(斤)[SIC]呀 那個小豬
Fifty seven "jin", that piggy.
#真的是成豬啦 太胖啦
It's really an adult now, too fat.
#下次要給它減一下肥
It needs to be on diet57